#### Yushan Yan

## Southampton, UK

## evayan1220@gmail.com

#### 07536957021

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yushan-yan-93b441230/

https://evayan.co.uk/

#### **Profile**

I am a passionate web developer and designer based in the UK, specializing in creating stunning, userfriendly websites and applications. Dedicated to user satisfaction, I possess strong UI/UX design skills to create visually engaging and intuitive websites. While my primary strength lies in developing robust, functional websites and applications, my understanding of design principles ensures these digital solutions are not only effective but also aesthetically pleasing. My aim is to develop intuitive and smooth websites that elevate the user's online experience.

#### **Technical skills**

## **Web Developer**

- HTML (Advanced)
- jQuery (Intermediate)
- React (Intermediate)
- PostgreSQL (Basic)
- CSS (Advanced)
- Git (Intermediate)
- Python (Basic)
- JavaScript (Intermediate)
- Bootstrap (Intermediate)
- PHP (Intermediate)

# Web Designer

- Adobe Illustrator (Advanced)
- Wordpress (Advanced)
- Adobe Photoshop (Intermediate)
- Adobe XD (Basic)
- Adobe Indesign (Intermediate)
- Figma (Intermediate)

#### Education

Professional Certification: Full-Stack Engineer (2023-2024)

**IT Career Switch** 

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git & GitHub, React, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, Web Security, Data Structures, Algorithms, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, Python Key modules: Web Development Foundations, Building Interactive Websites, Front-End

Development, Back-End Development, Full-Stack Development

Course Certificate: Fundamentals of Graphic Design (2022-2023)

Coursera

<u>Skills</u>: Creativity, Graphics, Design Theory, Color Theory, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign, Adobe Photoshop

Key modules: Imagemaking, Typography, Shape and Color, Composition

Course Certificate: Introduction to User Experience Design (2022-2023)

Coursera

<u>Skills</u>: Usability, User Experience (UX), User Experience Design (UXD), User Interface, Figma <u>Key modules</u>: Requirement Gathering, Designing Alternatives, Prototyping, Evaluation

MSc degree: Advanced Mechanical Engineering Science (2021-2022)

**University of Southampton** 

Dissertation: Potential Impact of Blockchain Technology in Biomedical Research

<u>Key modules</u>: Engineering Design with Management, Advanced Computational Methods (Python, C++)

BE degree: Mechanical and Electrical Engineering (First class) (2016-2020)

University of Beijing Information Science & Technology

Dissertation: The Construction of Machine Vision Experiment Platform

<u>Key modules</u>: C++ language Programming, Industrial Robot Engineering Application Training (Visual Studio 2010), Modeling and Simulation of Electromechanical System (Creo, AutoCAD, MATLAB) (Awarded certificate of outstanding graduate of Beijing as achieved the highest mark in the field of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering among ten thousand graduates.)

#### **Employment history**

Stelling Properties Limited, Winchester

Project and Design Engineer (September 2022 - June 2023)

- Designed Riser and MEP as individual assemblies for Type 5 Module.
- Collaborated with team members on 3D modeling and production packs for Ceiling Panel, Window Wall, Corridor Wall, Corridor End Panel, and A Frame Tooling.
- Led Riser prototype builds, conducted tests, and implemented updates based on testing feedback.
- Successfully implemented the Riser design in the Type 5 Module, marking a significant achievement.

My Anime Dream, Southampton

Sales Assistant (February 2022 – September 2022)

- Managed cash and card transactions, restocked products, and maintained store cleanliness.
- Assisted in planning product layout and implemented innovative ideas to boost sales.
- Actively communicated with customers to understand their needs and helped them find desired products.

## **Projects**

## We Buy Anime

 Designed and developed the website from scratch, including all UI/UX graphics and logo design.

#### Gazetteer

• Designed and developed an interactive map application providing detailed geographical information.

## **Company Directory**

• Completed the development of the application, significantly enhancing an initially unfinished project.

## **Cozy Petnest**

• Designed and developed the e-commerce website using WordPress, including all UI/UX graphics and logo design.

## **Additional Skills**

- Team working Communication Fast learner
- Time Management
  Problem-solving
  Adaptability

## References

Available on request.